[music]
in the pocket on third and Rush sacked
by Chris Jones. Stone cold. It's caught
by Kelsey inside the 10. Inside the
five. Kelsey leaps. Touchdown. KAREEM
HUNT AT THE 10. Angling to the five INTO
THE END ZONE LEFT SIDE AND IT is good.
[screaming] Good. Here comes a rush and
he's GOING TO GO DOWN. GEORGE CARLOS.
[music]
WELL, our final Chiefs rewind of the
season unfortunately is a loss as the
Chiefs lose here in Las Vegas to the
Raiders 14-12 on a career-long 60-yard
field goal by Daniel Carlson uh to win
the game after the Chiefs had a 41 yer
by Harrison Buckner to take a lead of 12
to1. But in many ways, this game was a
microcosm of the whole season. But a gut
punch feel to this one because it looked
like the Chiefs were on the verge of
winning it even though it wasn't pretty.
>> Yeah. a tough ending to what's been a
tough year for the Chiefs, right? Uh
this was our sixth loss this season by a
field goal or less. Think about that.
The margin has been so slim all year
long. And yeah, if we're being honest,
first of all, the Chiefs down a lot of
players in this game. It was not a
pretty football game by any means, but
they were right there till the very end
and had the lead in the final two
minutes. Just couldn't close it out. And
to your point, this really was a
microcosm of what the season was all
year long. Well, let's close the book
now on the 2025 season and attack 2026
because that work begins tomorrow.
>> Yeah, and part of the attack here deals
with some young defenders. Um, we saw
Tamari Connor jumped the route early,
get an interception that kind of flipped
the field to lead to a field goal for
the Chiefs, but then I thought Noah
Williams, he had an incredible sack um
early in the game, but his ability to
cover, we saw Jaden Hicks cover over the
top. He got beat on the play down the
rail on the winning drive of the field
goal, but we saw some athletic plays
made by him. Uh so there were some
encouraging signs from the younger
players, especially on defense.
>> Yeah, null Williams uh was exciting
today. Uh you talked about it a little
bit. He had two pass breakups in this
game. Uh nine tackles. He had that sack.
Almost had an interception. I think
he'll be kicking himself for that one.
It was right there. Just didn't expect
it. But uh he's going to be a player for
us. Uh he had sticky coverage on Tyler
Lockett on third down early in the game.
Just a lot of encouraging stuff from
null Williams here in this one. And also
Christian Fulton, you know, doesn't
really fit in the young player category,
but based on how his season has gone, we
kind of wanted to see him stack another
strong game here today. And I think he
did that. He had three three pass
breakups here in this game. Looking at
the offseason, I'm excited knowing what
we have in corner and null Williams and
Christian Fulton. And also Cooper
McDonald deserves mention here getting
line of scrimmage snaps u where playing
a strong side backer spot but then in
special teams he was stellar again in
this game uh and the fact and then let's
throw in Ethan DS you know who Ethan DS
is right he's the uh citizen of the
Osage nation so Creed Humphrey's the
podawatamy uh James Winchester's the
chalkaw but now we have Ethan DS who's a
member of the Osage nation but his hit
on the free kick return Yeah.
>> Allowed Cochran to get the fumble and
the Chiefs were able to get points out
of that. So, Cooper McDonald deserves
mention other than the fact that he's
close to getting 20 special teams
tackles.
>> Yeah, that's where this game has
meaning. Like, we get it. The game
doesn't get the Chiefs to the playoffs.
It doesn't have meaning in terms of the
standings. But, uh, tell that to guys
like Hooper McDonald and Ethan DS who
are playing for their NFL careers. And
McDonald has been a great story all year
long. I mean, this is a tryyout player.
Back in May, there were 60 try out
players just showing up with no
guarantees of a future in the NFL at
rookie mini camp back in May. Earned a
contract with this team. Earned a roster
spot uh way back in August. And now he's
played in all 17 games and played really
well here today. And with Downs, I mean,
yeah, this is an undrafted free agent, a
guy that joined the practice squad in
late August, I believe. Uh he'll, I'm
sure, be on this team as part of the
90-man roster over the course of the
offseason. And now we kind of know what
we have in him in terms of a special
teams ability because of that play here
today. So for him, let's build on that
now going into the offseason training
program.
>> Yeah, pride of Weatherford, Oklahoma,
Ethan DS. Offensively, there were some
moments. We're going to talk about that
a little bit later here in the show.
Chiefs lose it 14 to 12 on a field goal
by Daniel Carlson. A career long 60 yer,
but let's go to the podium now and get
reaction.
>> All right. Um, as far as the injuries
go, really there was nothing uh to give
you there. Uh, Michelle came out for a
little bit and went into be checked for
a concussion, but everything worked out
there. He was cleared. So, um, listen,
my my echoes off to the fans for all the
support they gave us throughout the the
season. Um, easily could have not shown
up um by some of the performances, but
they they they did a great job and we
appreciate that. uh optimistic for for
the future going forward here. Um uh
Brett's got the controls from here with
the draft and he he and his guys will do
a a great job there um in the draft and
as we work through free agency. So, um
and it was great to get the young guys
some play time. Uh if there was a
positive to take out of this whole
thing, I would tell you that's probably
the biggest positive there. Um other
than that, there were some there were
some uh nice accomplishments. Kelsey's
13,000 yards obviously was was a major
accomplishment there. [snorts] And then
to watch the veterans, Chris Jones come
in with a sack, Bolton have all the
tackles that he had. I mean, some of
these guys, Kel's playing, he played the
entire game really, as did the other
guys. So, Bucker getting back on track
there and having a few field goals. So,
again, those are all positive things
that you can take out and then seeing
some of our young guys uh step up and
makes make some plays uh uh throughout
the game. So, um, anyways, with that,
time's yours.
>> Andy, was the young guys in particular,
Bashard seemed to have some burst. What
What do you evaluate him?
>> Yeah, so I thought he he did a nice job
for us. Um, like the like the way he
caught the ball for the most part and
ran the ball. It was good to get him in
the back field running from the
different spots, offset and from uh
under center dot runs. Um, so
[clears throat] it was positive things.
He's just got he'll get stronger this
offseason. So that's the biggest thing
right now.
>> And with the quarterbacks, obviously you
went to Shane. What what did you see in
them? And and what did you see overall
in Chris?
>> Yeah, we told both guys to be ready to
go. Opportunity to play for both of
them. So, um I thought they both did
some good things. There's some things
that they can take from it and work on.
Um but there's nothing like live
experience and in a game and they both
got some. So they can utilize that down
the road. And with with Travis, I I know
you you'll you'll figure it's going to
be a process, but you've been through it
before with him the past. Are you going
to encourage him to take some time and
and how
>> Yeah, V. We'll just see where it goes.
We really haven't gone through that. So,
we we'll see where where it all goes
from here. Y
consider expectations and how the season
went for you personally, the challenges,
what to get through this season. Can you
sort of summarize for you um the success
that you've had during your career what
this season or what you endured in terms
of mentally to get through?
>> Yeah, sure. Nobody wants a season like
this. I mean, that's not what we strive
for and work work hard for, but they're
obstacles that that come into play and
you've got to work through those and
there's there's a learning curve here
that you can uh set uh with some of the
experiences we had for all of us and and
then [clears throat] never do it again,
right? So that's uh make a commitment to
that as coaches starting with me and and
the players, coaches included. Yeah.
>> Andy, you [clears throat] mentioned
being optimistic right away. What what
are the things you think of um that make
you say that right away?
>> Yeah. So we've got a a good nucleus of
guys. that's uh veteran players that
will be back and um I think that will
you want that foundation and and that's
where you start and then you give Brett
you know an opportunity to um have the
draft picks that he has and picking
where he's picking um [clears throat]
you know he's going to do a great job
there and and then whatever happens free
agent wise or guys we signed back you
know wherever that goes uh you still
have a long way to go to add people and
do what you need. So it it'll be a fresh
start coming up here.
>> Okay, good.
>> Chance now to be joined by one of the
best young corners in the National
Football League, Null Williams. Let's
just talk disappointment in this game,
but defensively you guys had some real
moments. How did you feel overall about
the uh team defensive effort?
>> Um we held him the three in the red
zone. We stood tall. I'm proud of my
guys. Um just fighting to the end. So
that's all you could ask for. effort,
you know, just we locked in on the
details when it came to it, you know. Of
course, you know, we want to end it
differently, of course, but I'm just
proud of the defensive unit, how we
stood tall and just kept playing.
>> Let's talk about your sack. You'll hear
it when I do the call. Man, you were a
missile on that thing. It's like he
never saw you. Were you invisible?
>> Um, I had got that same play in practice
and I had messed up. eventually I didn't
trigger and so I took the coaching
points and I seen I'm like oh wow this
is the play like if they block up two
the big wing I got to go so that was my
opportunity I you know thank thank
goodness I made the mistake early you
know and you know I capitalized in the
game so you know I was just good
coaching and I capitalized on
opportunity
>> again no null Williams with us rookie
cornerback the uh Matt and I have talked
about it talked about it last week you
had three passes, three tackles for
losses against the Broncos. For a DB,
that's like a year's worth. But today,
two passes broken up. How big was that
for you, especially in the concept of
this defense where you play a lot of
press?
>> It was really big. I knew they were
going to test me, you know, throwing the
ball wise. Um cuz last week I didn't I
had maybe a couple opportunities, but
this one I was more sticky in coverage
for sure. and uh going against great
receivers, you know, um number one and
then Tyler Lockett, the the vet, you
know, those are good guys. I respect
them and uh it was good competition out
there, you know.
>> Always say you like to play physical,
you like to play fast. Uh what about now
the offseason and trying to attack it to
get even better?
>> Offseason all about mastering the
playbook for me. um building up you know
my body make sure I you know I'm more
flexible more agile more fast faster and
just make sure you know my my sense my
cerebraless you know is make sure it's
everything's tight and I'm ready to go
for OTAAS
>> and then how big is it for technique to
cuz this league is so precise
>> technique is everything you know you
don't have to you know some people are
just great athletes and they don't have
to have technique you know but it's
still going to catch up to you at the
end of the day going against another
great athlete on the field. So technique
is everything. You know, everything at
the line, disrupting the line of
scrimmage, it may not look pretty, but
if you perfect it and you're trying it
and it it's going to work. So just keep
trusting the coach and keep trusting
myself.
>> Disappointing end of the season, but
we're not disappointed in this game. In
fact, we're excited to see what he's got
lined up for 2026. No Williams. Yeah, I
appreciate you, brother. Two dot, stay
on it.
>> Um, just areas of improvement. as a
tough year for us as a team and some of
the areas we can improve on individually
and um as a group. So looking for the
for ways that I can improve for next
year.
>> Chris, if in fact this is the last game
for Travis Kelce, what are you going to
remember most about your guy?
>> I'm not dying it. He'll be back next
year.
>> Is that a promise? I can't promise you
anything about another man, but I just
don't I don't know. I don't know. This
year was a tricky year for us. Um, I got
faith my dog coming back.
>> Chris, what what makes Travis the
teammate that he is? And and just to the
point of your friendship with him, what
what is it that's makes him that way for
you? It's just when you're a granddaddy
of a team and you've been here for
decades and
you know came in such a handsome guy and
now you got gray hairs and No, I'm just
playing with y'all. [clears throat]
[laughter] No, Travis is Travis, man.
He's um brings a lot of energy, a lot of
passion to the game. Uh one of the best
tight ends to ever play the game, if not
the best tight end to ever play the
game. And I have so much respect and
love for him. and he he has the best
cookies. I got to give it to him.
>> It seems like me reaches across the room
to a lot of guys, but you guys seem to
have a special relationship
particularly. What What's the key to
that relationship?
>> Travis is my hero.
Inside joke. He he'll understand,
but he he's my dog. Um hopefully this
isn't our last year. We have so much
more growth to do next year and so much
work to do and um I'm looking forward to
it. Do you remember just your first
impressions of him when you were a
rookie first coming in? Maybe first
training camp.
>> He was just catching everything.
>> What about personalitywise?
>> He was dancing to everything. Also,
dancing and catching everything. So, I
was like, you know what? I'm going to
start dancing. So, it's always been a
fun, energetic individual who brings the
energy, gives the group um fire to keep
going. So, I just prayed this isn't my
my dog last time.
>> Is that kind of unfinished business for
everybody coming back next year on
season?
>> Absolutely. I think this this season
didn't go as planned. Um, a lot of
valuable lessons learned throughout the
year and it's a lot of things we can
take from this year and look forward to
next year training camp.
>> Chris, you were highly motivated
obviously after last season. How will it
feel, do you think, going into this off
season? Is it a comparable kind of
feeling or a totally different sort of
emotion how you go into the offseason?
>> I think especially the way this year
ended, I'll be even more motivated
to to get this season started, you know,
um just the way this season ended. Um
been here 10 years, first time being in
this position. So [clears throat]
definitely a lot of motivation coming on
my end, especially finishing the way we
did. Last one.
>> Thank you.
>> Chiefs lose it here 14 to 12 to the
Raiders and finished six and 11 on the
season. Offensively, the 51yd pass to
Hollywood Brown from Shane Buchelle
deserves some mention cuz it's a heck of
a play and gave the Chiefs a chance to
win it cuz when Bucker hit the 41 yd
field goal, you're thinking 12 to1 11,
the Chiefs might come out of here with a
win.
>> Yeah. You know, we talk about culture
and championship and winning culture.
And even though this was not a pretty
game for the Chiefs by any means. To me,
that is championship culture where
things are not going well. Buchelle gets
sacked for that safety. Uh it doesn't
look like it's going to be our day. But,
uh, some things happen, the Chiefs find
their way back into the game. And for
Buchelle to keep on firing, you know, we
always tell Patrick Mahomes to keep on
firing no matter what happens. For
Buchelle when things had not gone well
earlier in the game, to find Hollywood
deep down the field, I thought that was
pretty cool. So, not a lot to hang our
hat on here today, but I'll look back at
that play and smile for sure.
>> Yeah, and Chris Hodokulken backed up
some in this game. Two lost fumbles were
critical, led to six points. And this
this game had 27 possessions and no
touchdowns. I remember seeing that in my
brief 32 years in the NFL. So, every
little thing matters. And those two lost
fumbles were rough to overcome even
though the Chiefs got to take away.
>> You know, football is humbling. The NFL
is humbling. And you know, we always
talk about you might be really good one
week and you're feeling great about
yourself and then next week something
bad happens. Well, how do you respond to
it? And that's kind of the message I
think for the Chiefs throughout this
offseason training program is how do you
respond to a season like this? Because
it was a lot of little things that just
added up over the course of the year.
Looking at another positive though, I
mean, Bashard Smith had 12 carries in
this game. Career high for him
obviously. Uh 56 yards on the ground. He
averaged 4.7 yards per rush. excited to
see what we have in Bashard here over
the course of the next several months.
>> Again, we do not know if this is Travis
Kelce's last game or not, but let's just
walk through some things here.
>> Uh three catches for 12 yards. Uh but he
gets to 13,000 yards. Just barely passed
it. But what he did with that uh
milestone catch was the fact that he was
the fastest uh 192 games to get to
13,000 yards. The fastest by a tight end
to get to that incredible mark. 191
straight games with a catch going all
the way back to September 7th, 2014. Uh
that puts him fourth all time of any
pass catcher. Uh so Travis Kelce, even
though this game didn't end the way he
wanted to and again, don't know if he's
coming back or not, but if he's not, and
we'll talk more about him, all the rest
of the Lord gives us oxygen on the
earth, I'll talk about this guy, but uh
phenomenal player and he was giving it
all he had in this game.
>> Yeah, he was. Here's a few more for you.
He passed Terrell Owens for the eighth
most catches in NFL history today. Think
about that. Terrell Owens, a Pro
Football Hall of Famer. Travis Kelce
passed him today. He also reached the 75
catch mark for the 10th straight year,
tying Tim Brown, who has the NFL record.
So, I mean, Travis Kelce is one of one.
Uh, we think he's the greatest tight end
of all time, one of the greatest pass
catchers to ever play this game. We saw
him go out there and play football here
today, and that's a blessing in its own.
and played if this is it his entire
career as a Kansas City Chief and also
>> 12,000 like 150 snaps. It'll I'll get
the update but crazy.
>> Really crazy.
>> Well, this is it. Chiefs go to 6 and 11
and we get ready for the 2026 year right
away. You've been awesome all this year.
This has [laughter] been a tough year
together. Usually we've been doing Super
We want a Super Bowl right here. Yeah.
>> Uh but we're uh
>> we'll take a back up a little bit but
then attack 2026. We're going to have
coverage from the combine. Uh this draft
is the most important since the 2022
draft and so a lot's on the plate moving
forward and I look forward to moving
forward with you.
>> Yeah, likewise, my friend. You're the
absolute best and you know, I think this
season has added a lot of perspective
for all of us. Uh we're used to winning
championships, right? And like you said,
we won a Super Bowl in this building not
too long ago. Bit of a different feeling
here today, but how do we get back to
that? It's about attacking the off
season right away. And we have the ninth
overall pick in the draft. I mean, what
an opportunity this is for the Chiefs to
set up the second leg of this dynasty,
right? I mean, for me, this is a setback
this year, not the end. Let's attack
2026.
>> Yeah. First top 10 pick since the Chiefs
traded up to take Patrick Mahomes in the
2017 draft. He's Matt McMullen, our
senior team reporter on Machultus, Voice
of the Chiefs, closing out a 32nd year
as the voice of the Chiefs. Thanks for
joining us all year long. We'll stay
right on it all the way up to training
camp to get you ready.
Chiefs Rewind is brought to you by Ford,
the official car and truck of the Kansas
City Chiefs, and by Community America
Credit Union, the official banking
partner of the Kansas City Chiefs.